Contact

k.l.ashwanthram@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ashwanthram (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Vector Databases
Large Language Models (LLM)
Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Tamil (Native or Bilingual)

Hindi (Elementary)

Certifications

JavaScript

Participated in the Guinness World Record Event

Java(Basic)

Python(Basic)

Problem Solving (Basic)

Honors-Awards
ACM ICPC

Ashwanthram K L

Data Scientist Intern @ FarmwiseAl Pvt Ltd | Large Language Models | GenAl | NLP | RAG

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Summary

Our team at FarmwiseAl Pvt Ltd is pioneering the integration of Language Models and Retrieval Augmented Generation, enhancing Al systems' decision-making capabilities. With a Bachelor of Engineering underway at Coimbatore Institute of Technology, my focus is on pushing the boundaries of Generative Al. Specializing in Vector Databases, Large Language Models, and Retrieval Augmented Generation, I am driving innovation that couples academic insights with industry applications.

During my internship, I've utilized LLMs and built various LLMpowered applications leveraging tools and frameworks such as Langchain, LlamaIndex, ChromaDB, FAISS, etc...

Experience

FarmwiseAl Pvt Ltd
Data Scientist
August 2023 - Present (10 months)
Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

During my tenure at FAI, I had the opportunity to work extensively with Language Models (LLMs) and Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG). My primary responsibilities included:

- Developing LLM powered applications.
- Implementing RAG models to enhance the decision-making capabilities of our AI systems.
- Collaborating with a team of data scientists and engineers to design and deploy AI models.
- Utilizing various AI tools and frameworks such as Langchain, VectorDBs, etc. to build the applications.

Tioha
Engineering Intern

June 2021 - September 2021 (4 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Accomplished thorough testing of over 30 REST APIs using tools such as Postman, Swagger, and Wireshark.
- Implemented automation of more than 20 REST API tests using Postman scripts and node.js, resulting in a significant reduction of testing time by over 50%.
- Identified and resolved more than 15 logical and functional bugs and inconsistencies across design, front-end, and APIs.

Education

Coimbatore Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Science · (2020 - 2024)

SBOA School & Junior College class 12, Computer Science · (2006 - 2020)